Jewish Historical Society of Greater Hartford Collection 0013.123.001
Jewish Historical Society of Greater Hartford
- Series XVIII: Hall of Fame, 1980s
  - Hall of Fame for Greater Hartford Jewish Athletes/1984
  - Hall of Fame for Greater Hartford Jewish Athletes/1985
  - Hall of Fame for Greater Hartford Jewish Athletes/1986
  - Hall of Fame for Greater Hartford Jewish Athletes/1987
  - Hall of Fame for Greater Hartford Jewish Athletes/1988
  - Hall of Fame for Greater Hartford Jewish Athletes/1989
- Series XIX: 1990s-2000s
  - Hall of Fame for Greater Hartford Jewish Athletes/1990
  - Hall of Fame for Greater Hartford Jewish Athletes/1992
  - Hall of Fame for Greater Hartford Jewish Athletes/1995
  - Hall of Fame for Greater Hartford Jewish Athletes/1995
  - Hall of Fame for Greater Hartford Jewish Athletes/1997
  - Hall of Fame for Greater Hartford Jewish Athletes/1997
  - Hall of Fame for Greater Hartford Jewish Athletes/1998
  - Hall of Fame for Greater Hartford Jewish Athletes/2002
  - Hall of Fame for Greater Hartford Jewish Athletes/Honorees, undated
  - Hall of Fame for Greater Hartford Jewish Athletes/Policies and Procedures, undated
- Series XX: Historical Highlights - Meetings and Programs (other than annual meetings), 1970s-1980s
  - Meetings and Programs are filed chronologically by date of event., undated
  - Historical Highlights Meetings and Programs/1970s-1980s/Guest Book, 1970-1989
  - Meetings and Programs/1971 Sept. 9/Bernard Wax
  - Meetings and Programs/1972 June 28/ Judge Abraham S. Borden
  - Meetings and Programs/1972 May 10/Berthold Gaster
  - Meetings and Programs/1973 June 13/Cantor Arthur Koret
  - Meetings and Programs/1974 Dec. 12/Mt. Sinai Hospital/Dr. Isadore Geeter
  - Meetings and Programs/1974 June 19/Rabbi Avrutnick interview
  - Meetings and Programs/1974 Nov 22/Rae Neiditz interview
  - Meetings and Programs/1974 Nov. 6/Mark Sobotka interview
  - Meetings and Programs/1974 Sept. 22/Hartford Jews 1900-1925, documentary
  - Meetings and Programs/1975 April 22/Jenny Silver interview
  - Meetings and Programs/1975 Jan. 10/Herman Holz interview
  - Meetings and Programs/1975 March 3/Judge George Schwolsky interview
  - Meetings and Programs/1975 March 31/Rabbi Arthur A. Chiel "stiles and the Jews"
  - Meetings and Programs/1975 May 12/Melvin W. Title interview
  - Meetings and Programs/1975 Nov. 3/Bill Savitt interview
  - Meetings and Programs/1975 Oct. 8/Ezra Melrose interview
  - Meetings and Programs/1976 Feb. 11/Judge Leo Parsky
  - Meetings and Programs/1976 March 28/Rabbi Reuven Kimelman/Bibles' impact on founding fathers
  - Meetings and Programs/1976 May 12/Sadie Klau interview
  - Meetings and Programs/1976 Nov. 10/Judge Joseph Blumenfeld interview
  - Meetings and Programs/1976 Oct. 13/Emma Cohen Interview
  - Meetings and Programs/1976? /Mariana and David Eckstein/Russian Emigrants
  - Meetings and Programs/1977 April 13/Rabbi Philip Lazowski interview/
  - Meetings and Programs/1977 December 8/Berthold Gaster interview
  - Meetings and Programs/1977 February 9/Rita Cohn Interview
  - Meetings and Programs/1977 January 12/Judge Harry H. Kleinman interview
  - Meetings and Programs/1977 March 9/Moses Neiditz Interview
  - Meetings and Programs/1977 November 9/Seymour Saltzman/Making Your Family Tree
  - Meetings and Programs/1978 December 13/Henry D. Margolis/The Margolis Family of Craftsmen
  - Meetings and Programs/1978 June 2/History of the Reform Movement in Hartford/Rabbi Harold Silver
  - Meetings and Programs/1978 March 8/Rabbi Abraham Avrutnick/History of the Orthodox Movement in Hartford
  - Meetings and Programs/1978 May 18/History of the Conservative Movement in Hartford/Rabbi Stanley Kessler
  - Meetings and Programs/1978 September 13/Stephen Joel Trachtenberg
  - Meetings and Programs/1979 April 4/Holocaust Commemoration/Peter Korduner interview
  - Meetings and Programs/1979 December 12/Fran Waltman/Yiddish Theater in Hartford 1901-1910
  - Meetings and Programs/1979 March 14/Alfred Weisel/the History of Jewish Education in the Greater Hartford Area
  - Meetings and Programs/1979 May 9, Dr. M. Delott Garber, interview
  - Meetings and Programs/1979 November 8/Ethnic History of Hartford – videotape
  - Meetings and Programs/1979 October11/Golden Age of Jewish Music in Hartford/Cantor Arthur Koret
  - Meetings and Programs/1980 April 10/Holocaust Commemoration/Rabbi Hans Bodenheimer
  - Meetings and Programs/1980 February 20/Daniel Peer
  - Meetings and Programs/1980 March 13/Daniel Peer, Scholar-in-Residence/The Current Political Situation in the Mideast
  - Meetings and Programs/1980 May 8/Rabbi Howard Berman The Beauty of Holiness
  - Meetings and Programs/1980 November 13/Irving and Belle Berkowetz Cutler (COPACO)
  - Meetings and Programs/1980 October 9/Soviet Synagogues and Refusenicks visited
  - Meetings and Programs/1981 November 1/Prof. Walter Cahn at Trinity College
  - Meetings and Programs/1982 February 22/Contemporaary Israel: An American Settler's Perspective/Robert Rockaway/
  - Meetings and Programs/1982 March 4/Robert A. Rockaway/American Jewish Congress, joint program
  - Meetings and Programs/1982 May 19/Our Society: A Look at the Future
  - Meetings and Programs/1982 September 9/Jerry Wagner Interview
  - Meetings and Programs/1983 April 14/How the Fiddler got on the Roof
  - Meetings and Programs/1983 December 8/Bert Welk Interview
  - Meetings and Programs/1983 March 10/The Greater Hartford Jewish Federation: Its History, Growth, and Development
  - Meetings and Programs/1984 December 13/Meet the Author: Kenneth Libo
  - Meetings and Programs/1984 June 14/An Evening with David T. Chase
  - Meetings and Programs/1984 May 10/Dr. Leonard Menczer
  - Meetings and Programs/1984 November 8/An evening at the Connecticut Historical Society
  - Meetings and Programs/1984 September 13/The First Experience: the Immigrant and the Statue of Liberty/Ira Yellin
  - Meetings and Programs/1984/Precious Legacy
  - Meetings and Programs/1985 April 25/An Interview with Simon Konover
  - Meetings and Programs/1985 June 27/Arlene Neiditz and Vivian Zoë
  - Meetings and Programs/1985 March 14/Dr. Nathan Mayer/A Research Study by Dr. Irving
  - Meetings and Programs/1986 March 16/An Exclusive Interview with Julius Berman
  - Meetings and Programs/1986 September 30/Dr. Jonathan Rosenbaum
  - Meetings and Programs/1987 April 23/Herman Holtz re Ados Israel
  - Meetings and Programs/1987 March 12/Ellsworth Grant
  - Meetings and Programs/1988 April 5/Hartford in 1948
  - Meetings and Programs/1989 April 4/David Dalin/Researching and Writing Local Jewish History
  - Meetings and Programs/1989 April 6/A Celebration of Yiddish Musical Theatre
  - Meetings and Programs/1989 Dec. 6/JCC book and Craft Fair/Lothar Kahn, Irving Waltman, David Dalin
  - Meetings and Programs/1989 March 16\Records Management in Synagogues
- Series XXI: Meetings and Programs (Other than Annual Meetings 1990s-2000s
  - Meetings and Programs/ca. 1990s/14th Annual Jewish Book Festival, undated
  - Meetings and Programs/1991 Nov. 4/Henry Levy Interview
  - Meetings and Programs/1991 November 20/Hartford's South End/Irving and Fran Waltman
  - Meetings and Programs/1993 November 14/Paid Up Membership/Joan Rosenbaum
  - Meetings and Programs/1993/Historical Research Through Personal Perspective
  - Meetings and Programs/1994 March 10/Stave and Sunderland, From the Old Country
  - Meetings and Programs/1994 Oct. 19/Irving Waltman interview
  - Meetings and Programs/1995 Nov. 5/Rabbi Hillel Silverman
  - Meetings and Programs/1996 March 12/Leon Chameides/Jews of Prague
  - Meetings and Programs/1996 May 14/Joyce Miller/They Came for Good
  - Meetings and Programs/1997 Dec. 7/Paid Up Membership/Ann Louise Gittleman
  - Meetings and Programs/1997-1998/Yiddish Festival
  - Meetings and Programs/1998 December. 20/Paid Up Membership/Arik Rosenblum
  - Meetings and Programs/1998 June 4/Scrapbooking
  - Meetings and Programs/1998 May 3/Rabbi Haskel Lendenthal interview
  - Meetings and Programs/1998 November 10/Lita Weis Marks, Time's Tapestry
  - Meetings and Programs/1998/Connecticut Visions, with Connecticut Historical Society
  - Meetings and Programs/1999 April 11/Yiddle on his Fiddle
  - Meetings and Programs/1999 April 19/Remembering Abraham Goldstein
  - Meetings and Programs/1999 April 23/Passover Haggadah
  - Meetings and Programs/1999 Nov. 21/200 Years of an American Ethnic Family
  - Meetings and Programs/1999/Paid up Membership/Bernard Lurie
  - Meetings and Programs/1999-2000/Ideas
  - Meetings and Programs/1999-2000/Yiddish Festival
  - Meetings and Programs/2000 Nov. 5/Dr. Leon Chameides
  - Meetings and Programs/2001 April 22/Heritage Award
  - Meetings and Programs/2001 Nov. 18/Marjorie Rafal
  - Meetings and Programs/2001/May-June/Visas for Life
  - Meetings and Programs/2002/Anniversaries/30th/Honoring Past Presidents
  - Meetings and Programs/2003/Jews of Kaifeng
  - Meetings and Programs/2003/Yiddish Festival
  - Meetings and Programs/2004/Arnold Dashefsky, the American Jewish Experience: 1654-2004
  - Meetings and Programs/2004/Rabbi Okalika
  - Meetings and Programs/2006/Voices of Philanthropy
  - Meetings and Programs/2007/Annual Meeting
  - Meetings and Programs/2007/Joyce Antler
  - Meetings and Programs/2007/Margolis Furniture
  - Meetings and Programs/2008
  - Meetings and Programs/2008/Jews of China
  - Meetings and Programs/2008/Scream the Truth at the World: Emanuel Ringelblum and the Hidden Archive of the Warsaw Ghetto
  - Meetings and Programs/2009
  - Meetings and Programs/April 26, 2009/ Leon Chameides presentation on Mount Sinai (includes PowerPoint on CD) see Mount Sinai collection, box 4
  - Meetings and Programs/2009/Jews of the Venetian Ghetto
  - Meetings and Programs/2010/Echoes and Reflections
- Series XXIa: Programs and Events
  - Doris and Simon Konover Event, September 7, 2008
  - Hartford Bus Tour/ "Back to the Old Neighborhood", 2012; newspaper clippings (Box 21a)
    Jewish Historical Society of Greater Hartford
  - "Jews of China", undated
  - "Oral History – How to do it? Why to do it?" September 29, 2008
  - Out of the Archives, undated
  - Sophie Tucker Exhibit, June 3, 2007
  - North End Project, February 8, 2008 –
  - National Yiddish Book Center, April 6, 2008
  - Scream the Truth at the World: Emanuel Ringlebloom April 11, 2008
  - Senator Dodd, September 14, 2008
  - Virginia Hale Beatrice Fox Aurbach Book Talk, October 30, 2008
  - Time Capsule, January 16, 2009
  - Lecture by Brandeis Professor Joyce Antler, October 18, 2009
  - JHSGH 40th Anniversary Gala, 2011-2012
  - JHSGH Programs & Events 2012
- Series XXIb: Programs & Events
  - Historical Society Programs and Events/Celebrating 30 Years, undated
  - Historical Society Programs and Events/JHS Schwartz, undated
  - Historical Society Programs and Events/"Out of the Archives", undated
  - Historical Society Programs and Events/Sophie Tucker Exhibit, undated
  - Historical Society Programs and Events/North End Project, undated
  - Historical Society Programs and Events/National Yiddish Book Center, undated
  - Historical Society Programs and Events/"Scream the Truth at the World: Emanuel Ringlebloom….", undated
  - Historical Society Programs and Events/"Doris and Simon Konover Event", undated
  - Historical Society Programs and Events/Senator Dodd, undated
  - Historical Society Programs and Events/Workshop/Oral History-How to do it? Why to do it?, undated
  - Historical Society Programs and Events/"Virginia Hale's Beatrice Fox Aurbach Book Talk, undated
  - Historical Society Programs and Events/"The Jews of China", undated
  - Historical Society Programs and Events/Time Capsule, undated
  - Historical Society Programs and Events/Lecture by Brandeis Professor Joyce Antler, undated
  - Historical Society Programs and Events/Recalling 500 Blue Hills Ave, undated
  - Historical Society Programs and Events/Roth Exhibit, undated
  - Historical Society Programs and Events/Historical Photos for Programs, undated
  - Historical Society Programs and Events 2002-2008
  - Historical Society Programs and Events/Misc 2009
  - Historical Society Programs and Events/Misc 2010
  - Historical Society Programs and Events/Misc 2011
- Series XXII: Meetings and Programs/Annual Meetings: Members and Membership/Membership Lists
  - Meetings and Programs/Annual Meeting/1972/First Annual Meeting/Franchon Title interview
  - Meetings and Programs/Annual Meeting/1976/Bernard Wax
  - Meetings and Programs/Annual Meeting/1977/Samuel D. Kassow
  - Meetings and Programs/Annual Meeting/1979/Doris Schwartz Hurwit
  - Meetings and Programs/Annual Meeting/1980/Honoring Emma Cohen/Bernard Wax speaker
  - Meetings and Programs/Annual Meeting/1982/Benjamin Varon
  - Meetings and Programs/Annual Meeting/1985/Irving and Fran Waltman
  - Meetings and Programs/Annual Meeting/1987/Emma Cohen Jewish History Awards
  - Meetings and Programs/Annual Meeting/1988/Dr. Kenneth Libo People in Print
  - Meetings and Programs/Annual Meeting/1990/Gertude Ogushwitz
  - Meetings and Programs/Annual Meeting/1991/20th Anniversary/Henry S. Cohn
  - Meetings and Programs/Annual Meeting/1994/Bernard Wax/Tribute to Marsha Lotstein
  - Meetings and Programs/Annual Meeting/1995/Lenn Zonder
  - Meetings and Programs/Annual Meeting/1996/Jonathan Rosenbaum
  - Meetings and Programs/Annual Meeting/1997/25th Anniversary/Llyn Kaimowitz
  - Meetings and Programs/Annual Meeting/1998/John W. Shannahan
  - Meetings and Programs/Annual Meeting/1999/Dr. David Shuldiner
  - Meetings and Programs/Annual Meeting/2000/Dr. Betty Hoffman
  - Meetings and Programs/Annual Meeting/2001/Vivian Zoë
  - Meetings and Programs/Annual Meeting/2002/David Jacobs
  - Meetings and Programs/Annual Meeting/2007/Elliot Pollock
  - Meetings and Programs/Annual Meeting/2007/Elliot Pollock
  - Meetings and Programs/OVERSIZE, in oversize box on shelf, undated
  - Meetings and Programs/undated/Honorable Saul Seidman interview
  - Members and Membership/1980s/Annual Members, undated
  - Members and Membership/Life Memberships, undated
  - Members and Membership/Life Memberships/solicitation/1994-1995, undated
  - Members and Membership/Membership Letters/1980s, undated
  - Members and Membership/Membership Letters/1990s, undated
  - Members and Membership/Membership Letters/n.d., undated
  - Members and Membership/Membership Lists/1988
  - Members and Membership/Membership Lists/1992
  - Members and Membership/Membership Lists/1993
  - Members and Membership/Membership Lists/1996
  - Members and Membership/Membership Lists/1997-1998
  - Members and Membership/Membership Lists/1999
  - Members and Membership/Membership Lists/2000
  - Members and Membership/Membership Lists/2001
- Series XXIII: Members and Membership/New Members - Organizations
  - Members and Membership/New Members/1988-1989/1989-1990/1990-1991, 1988-1991
  - Members and Membership/New Members/1992-1993
  - Members and Membership/New Members/1993-1994
  - Members and Membership/New Members/1994-1995 and 1995-1996
  - Members and Membership/New Members/1996-1997
  - Members and Membership/New Members/1997-1998
  - Members and Membership/New Members/1998-1999
  - Members and Membership/New Members/1999-2000
  - Members and Membership/Prospective Member List and Letter, undated
  - Newsletters – see boxes 23a and 23b, undated
  - Newspapers Clippings/1970s, 1970-1979
  - Newspapers Clippings/1980s, 1980-1989
  - Newspapers Clippings/1990s, 1990-1999
  - Newspaper Clippings/2000s, 2000-2009
  - Organizations/GHJCC/Book Festival/1993-1996
  - Organizations/GHJCC/Book Festival/1997-1999
  - Organizations/GHJCC/Book Festival/2000-2003
  - Organizations/Trinity College/Hillel, undated
- Series XIIIa, b, c: Newsletters, The Heritage
  Heritage, The (JHSGH quarterly newsletter)
  - Newsletters: 1970s-1980s
  - Newsletters 1990s-2003
  - Newsletters 2004-2006
  - Newsletters 2007, 2007-2007
  - Newsletters 2008-2009
  - Newsletters 2010-2012
- Series XXIV: Outreach: Publications/Connecticut Jewish History, Volume I
  - Outreach/Lotstein, Marsha/Presentations to other organizations, undated
  - Outreach/Miscellaneous, undated
  - Outreach/Miscellaneous, undated
  - Publications/Connecticut Jewish History/Connecticut History Journals/Editors, undated
  - Publications/Connecticut Jewish History/Volume 1 and 2/Marketing, undated
  - Publications/Connecticut Jewish History/Volume 1/Correspondence/Kahn, Lothar, undated
  - Publications/Connecticut Jewish History/Volume 1/Endowment Grant, 1989, undated
  - Publications/Connecticut Jewish History/Volume 1/Final copy, undated
  - Publications/Connecticut Jewish History/volume 1/Journal Committee Minutes, 1988-1990, undated
  - Publications/Connecticut Jewish History/Volume 1/Miscellaneous Materials from Lothar Kahn, undated
  - Publications/Connecticut Jewish History/volume 1/original submissions, undated
  - Publications/Connecticut Jewish History/Volume 1/Printing and Publishing Information, undated
  - Publications/Connecticut Jewish History/Volume 1/Research Notes/Kopplemann, undated
  - Publications/Connecticut Jewish History/Volume 1/Research Notes/Kahn, Lothar, undated
- Series XXV: Publications/Connecticut Jewish History, v. 2 and 3/2012
  - Publications/Connecticut Jewish History/Volume 2/fundraiser, undated
  - Publications/Connecticut Jewish History/Volume 2/General, undated
  - Publications/Connecticut Jewish History/Volume 2/Manuscript/Draft, undated
  - Publications/Connecticut Jewish History/Volume 2/Marketing, undated
  - Publications/Connecticut Jewish History/Volume 2/Mechanicals Cover, undated
  - Publications/Connecticut Jewish History/Volume 2/100 years: Synagogue architectural survey, undated
  - Publications/Connecticut Jewish History/Volume 3/Committee, undated
  - Publications/Connecticut Jewish History/Volume 3/Patrons and Sponsors, undated
  - Publications/Making a Life: Building a Community, see JHSGH/Special Projects and University of Hartford and Morris and Emma Cohen Collections, undated
- Series XXVI: Publicity
  - Publicity/Bookmarks, undated
  - Publicity/Brochures, undated
  - Publicity/Brochures, undated
  - Publicity/Brochures, 1971-1972
  - Publicity/Brochures, 1972-1973
  - Publicity/Brochures, 1973-1974
  - Publicity/Brochures, 1974-1975
  - Publicity/Brochures, 1975-1976
  - Publicity/Brochures, 1976-1977
  - Publicity/Brochures, 1977-1978
  - Publicity/Brochures, 1978-1979
  - Publicity/Brochures, 1979-1980
  - Publicity/Brochures, 1980-1981
  - Publicity/Brochures, 1981-1982
  - Publicity/Brochures, 1983-1984
  - Publicity/Brochures, late 1980s and early 1990s, undated
  - Publicity/Logo, undated
  - Publicity/OVERSIZE, in oversize box on shelf, undated
- Series XXVII: Trips and Tours
  - Trips and Tours/1975 June 18/Brandeis University
  - Trips and Tours/1976 May 10/New York City
  - Trips and Tours/1977 May 4/New York City
  - Trips and Tours/1978 May 1/Hartford
  - Trips and Tours/1979 May 15/New York City
  - Trips and Tours/1979 Nov. 4/Old State House and Wadsworth Atheneum
  - Trips and Tours/1980 April 24/New York City
  - Trips and Tours/1980 Nov. 20/Hartford Architecture
  - Trips and Tours/1981 April 1/Boston MA
  - Trips and Tours/1981 Aug. 10/Charter Oak Temple
  - Trips and Tours/1982 May 5/New York City
  - Trips and Tours/1987 April 30/New York City
  - Trips and Tours/1993 Aug. 1-3/Washington DC
  - Trips and Tours/1994 June 12-14/Washington DC
  - Trips and Tours/1996 Aug 18-20/Washington DC
  - Trips and Tours/Games, undated
- Series XXVIII: Special Projects/Miscellaneous
  - "Special Projects" include ventures that comprised several facets such as an exhibit, publication, and meeting program, or which didn't fall into any of these three categories., undated
  - Special Projects/1954/Tercentenary, undated
  - Special Projects/1970s-present/Oral History, undated
  - Special Projects/1978/Roots
  - Special Projects/1982/Jewish War Veterans
  - Special Projects/1982/Emanuel Synagogue
  - Special Projects/1983/Jewish Day
  - Special Projects/1989/Grocery Stores
  - Special Projects/1996/Archives
  - Special Projects/1998/Tribute to Lewis Fox at Fox Middle School, with Eve Soumerai
  - Special Projects/2002/Greater Hartford Jewish Community History Project, funded by Zachs Family Foundation
  - Special Projects/2002/Memoirs/Trips to Israel
  - Special Projects/2002/Memoir Workshop
  - Special Projects/1999-2002/Memoir workshop/Leader: Len Cohen
  - Special Projects/2006/North End/Oral History
- Series XXIX: Special Projects/1995/Soviet Jewish World War II Exhibit/Jewish War Veterans
  - Nov. 2000 Betty Hoffman/ JFS citizenship class at Beth Israel, undated
  - Newest Americans, Betty Hoffman, undated
  - Soviet Jewish Experience Esfir Kraimore, undated
- Series XXX: Special Projects/2009/Hartford North End Project
  - Special Projects/2009/Hartford North End Book/Book Launch
  - Special Projects/2009/Hartford North End Book/Book: Remembering the Old Neighboorhood
  - Special Projects/2009/Hartford North End Book/Interview Information
  - Special Projects/2009/Hartford North End Book/Jewish Ledger
  - Special Projects/2009/Hartford North End Book/North End Narrators/DVD
  - Special Projects/2009/Hartford North End Book/PowerPoint shown at Book Opening/Photographs
  - Special Projects/2009/Hartford North End Book/Publicity
  - Special Projects/2009/Hartford North End Book/Request for Information/Stories
  - Special Projects/2009/Hartford North End /Donated Photos/October 2009
  - Special Projects/2009/Hartford North End /Donated Photos/2010
  - Special Projects/Hartford North End/Leadership Greater Hartford North End program, undated
- Series XXXI: Special Projects/2012/Hartford North End Project II
  - Special Projects/Hartford North End/Book II/Donated Images/ 2010, undated
  - Special Projects/Hartford North End/Book II/Elston, Rosalyn Millstein, undated
  - Special Projects/Hartford North End/Book II/Images 2010-2012, undated
  - Witness to War, undated
  - Witness to War: The Soviet Jewish Experience 1941-1945 was a major traveling exhibit conceived of and created by the JHSGH. The project involved the interviewing and videotaping of numerous Russian-Americans of the World War II generation. The project resulted in two end products: the traveling exhibit and a volume of Connecticut Jewish History dedicated to the topic. This collection contains the original videotapes, transcripts in both Russian and English, and administrative files related to the project., undated
  - Witness to War was coordinated by JHSGH Director Marsh Lotstein and Dr. Betty Hoffman, historian. The exhibit was designed by Harrison (Whitey) Jenkins. Jeffrey Mills designed the brochure and Diana McCain provided publicity services., undated
  - Special Projects/Witness to War, Box 1: Witness Transcripts, undated
  - Special Projects/Witness to War/Transcripts/Russian/Witness List, undated
  - Special Projects/Witness to War/Transcripts/Russian/Aronov, Marc, undated
  - Special Projects/Witness to War/Transcripts/Russian/Domnich, Genya, undated
  - Special Projects/Witness to War/Transcripts/Russian/Frenkel, Mariya, undated
  - Special Projects/Witness to War/Transcripts/Russian/Freydzoh, Gdal, undated
  - Special Projects/Witness to War/Transcripts/Russian/Gekhman, Aron, undated
  - Special Projects/Witness to War/Transcripts/Russian/Ginsburg, Boris, undated
  - Special Projects/Witness to War/Transcripts/Russian/Grabarnik, Lazar, undated
  - Special Projects/Witness to War/Transcripts/Russian/Gupper, Naum, undated
  - Special Projects/Witness to War/Transcripts/Russian/Izikson, Abram, undated
  - Special Projects/Witness to War/Transcripts/Russian/Kaganovich, Israel, undated
  - Special Projects/Witness to War/Transcripts/Russian/Kaplan, Vladimir, undated
  - Special Projects/Witness to War/Transcripts/Russian/Khaimova, Esfir, undated